What happens if you drink a glass of unboiled tap water here in Taiwan?
Continue watching and find out.
After four years and interviewing countless of foreigners here on the channel,
I think we can all agree on three things.
Taiwan is clean, safe, and it's also surrounded by water.
But is the water in Taiwan just as clean and safe as the rest of the island?
Well, this might sound like a very simple question with a yes or no answer,
but it actually depends on who, where, and how you ask the question.
And this question is actually something that I asked myself,
or, well, I asked Google, 13 years ago before the first time coming here to Taiwan.
Because I don't know about you, but for me, every time I travel to a new country,
there are three questions I always want an answer to.
And the first one is, what kind of currency are they using in Taiwan in this example?
What kind of power outlets are they using in Taiwan?
And the third one is, can you actually drink the tap water in Taiwan?
Now, this is where it starts to get a little complicated,
because the first answer from Google is, the tap water in Taiwan is not very safe to drink.
And this is actually an official link from National Chongqing University's medical information page
for new potential international students coming here to Taiwan.
But if you instead would Google, can you drink the tap water in Taipei?
The first answer is actually a link to the Taipei Water Department,
which clearly states in the first sentence, and I quote,
the water supplied by Taipei Water Department is definitely safe for drinking.
But even with this very confident statement from Taipei Water Department,
I have, during my 12 years here in Taiwan, never seen anyone actually drinking tap water.
And to all of you who will say, Lucas, what are you talking about?
Drinking tap water is totally fine.
All you have to do is first filter it, and then boil it, and then you can drink as much as you want.
If your argument is that you can drink tap water as long as you boil it,
it's basically like saying, I can walk on water just like Jesus.
All you have to do is to freeze it first.
At least in my book, it just doesn't really count if you have to either boil or filter tap water before drinking it.
Anyway, the point I'm trying to make is that although Taipei Water Department
says that the water supplied by them is definitely safe to drink,
no one actually seems to be drinking it.
And during my 12 years and my personal non-scientific research at all,
I think that the main reason for this is that people are a little bit scared
since they live in older buildings that have older water pipes,
and they're not entirely sure what actually happens to the water
once it leaves Taipei Water Department and then comes into their own taps in their own apartments.
So how could you actually find out if your specific tap in your specific apartment
will provide you with clean, safe, drinkable tap water?
Actually, the only thing you need to do is to go and visit Taipei Water Department's website
where they have the entire article about the quality of tap water in English for everyone to read.
And this is my absolute favorite part.
If you live in Taipei metropolis and are concerned about your tap water,
please feel free to call us and we will answer your questions on the phone
or make a field survey and examine the water quality for you.
The service is free of charge.
Or you could actually bring your own water here to Taipei Water Department.
I should point out that this video is not sponsored by Taipei Water Department.
They have no idea I'm even recording this video.
And now when I am thinking about it, I actually may not be able to record inside.
But regardless, let's go in and check it out.
Well, as I should have known before actually starting recording this video,
is that you do need to apply for a permit in order to actually record inside Taipei Water Department.
But regardless, the whole process was actually super simple
and they also have all the instructions on their website as well.
The only thing you need to do basically is just to fill up a plastic bottle with water
and then you head over to their office slash water factory in Dan District.
Right next to the best area in entire Taipei, Liu Changli.
If you do not live here already, definitely consider moving here
because this area is amazing.
Anyway, I did want to point out a few things before you actually bring your water over to Taipei Water Department.
And that is, of course, that you need to keep the water running for three minutes before you take the sample.
You need to have a clear plastic bottle.
But then they actually only test your straight tap water straight from your tap supplied by them.
So filtered waters or any other kind of water that is not supposed to be for drinking, I guess,
would not really be tested by them.
And then all you have to do is just fill out a form and then actually when they're done with the testing,
which should happen the same day if you give it to samples before 12,
and they did say that if you actually had some issues with the water,
like if there's been some renovation and something has broken,
they might have to do some more advanced testing.
But this was a free test and you basically just get the real basic information telling you if it's drinkable or not.
But maybe you will not get the most analytical water levels and stuff.
I haven't seen the report yet, so I don't know how they look like.
So yeah, that's what we're waiting for right now.
And hopefully it will actually come here later today.
Otherwise, we don't have an ending for this video because I am going to go to Taidong tomorrow
and record another video over there.
So, yeah.
But while we are waiting, I do have some time to share some information regarding the sponsor of today's video,
which regardless of how this report from the Taipei Water Department looks like,
I guarantee you will take your love for water to a completely new level.
And I am of course talking about sparkling water from Celinda.
Now, normally when I am this excited, something really, really big has just happened.
But I think that this is the tiniest, biggest thing that has ever happened to me.
Because the SD300 sparkling water machine we recently installed in our apartment
is just a tiny little innocent water tap right next to our sink.
But please do not let the size fool you,
because this tap follows the Scandinavian approach of minimalistic design,
which we all love so much.
And all the magic is actually happening underneath the sink
with both a cooling pump and a tube full of sparkles.
Or, well, I guess, carbon dioxide,
since the technical term, I believe, is carbonated water and not sparkling water.
But, yeah, you get the point.
So, the water gets into this cooling pump
where you can actually control the specific degree of the water
from 1 to 12 degrees Celsius,
which means that you get the perfect temperature of water
every single time, right away,
as soon as you want your next glass.
And, and this is the magical part,
it's directly connected to this big tube of sparkles,
I mean carbon dioxide,
so you can get up to 490 liters of sparkling water
before you need to change the tube.
And honestly, I can just sit here for hours
talking about how incredible it is
to have your own sparkling water machine
built into the tap right next to your sink.
And also just how much better it is for the environment
compared to, like, going to 7-Eleven
and buying your daily, in my case,
sparkling water from these plastic bottles.
But there are no words in the world
who can describe just how incredibly cool it is
to just open up the tap
and get cold, sparkling water
straight from the tap, all the time.
I can go up in the middle of the night,
just flick the tap and get one tiny glass of sparkling water
before going back to sleep again
without having to go through the normal process
of first filling up a bottle of normal water,
putting it into a machine,
pressing a button for a few seconds,
taking the bottle and pouring it into a glass,
putting the rest of the bottle back into the fridge,
taking some ice cubes, putting it into my glass
in order to have an actually refreshing
glass of cold, sparkling water.
Now I can get a glass of sparkling water in literally
seconds, just as long as it would take
for me to pour up a glass of non-sparkling,
boring, old-fashioned
normal water.
But if this under-the-sink setup looks a little
bit intimidating, just know that Celinda will
of course come home to your apartment and install
this for you, so you do not need to lift
the finger at all. Except of course
when I actually had enough sparkling water
and want the machine to stop.
And it is actually the exact same process when
eventually you will run out of the 490
liters of sparkles.
If you do have these smaller containers,
then once you do run out after like
60 liters only, you are the one who
has to bring this to the department store
and then actually get it replaced there, and then bring it
back home again. Celinda will actually
come home with the new tank for you,
they will do the replacements, and then
you're ready to go in no time.
Now, there are a few things I want to make very clear,
especially considering the topic of today's video.
This is a sparkling water
machine, so it will actually add sparkles
or carbon dioxide to your water
and it also has a fridge
cooling function, so it will actually cool
down the water to your decided degree,
but it will not filter the water for you.
And Celinda is recommending
that you are using a separate filter system
which of course you can connect straight
into this under-the-sink machine,
just like we already had here in our apartment.
Secondly, if you for some reason
would not want to drink sparkling water
all the time, I don't really understand
why you wouldn't, the SD300
sparkling water machine does come with
a pass-through function as well, so you can get the
sparkling water from the left side, but if
you do want the original filtered water
without any sparkles to, for example,
fill up your coffee machine, you can get that
here on the right side as well.
And last but not least, if you want a little bit less
Scandinavian minimalistic approach, and a little bit more
show-off, majestic piece in your kitchen,
they also have other on-the-counter
design machines as well, which
will give you the same functions as the SD300
that we have in our kitchen,
but with this on-the-counter solution
instead. So please, do yourself a
favor, go check out Celinda's website
for a little bit more information, because I can
hand-on-heart 100%
say that this is
the best home
solution product, just
way of life, I have
ever experienced. I couldn't even dream
about this thing, but this is just a
completely different level, and
there is no going back
to drinking any other kind
of sparkling water. It is
absolutely amazing. I should also
mention, which I actually forgot,
you can actually also adjust the
amount of sparkles in the
tube as well, so if you have been worried
about that you cannot actually customize the amount
of sparkles,
you can. You can.
Yeah, that was it.
Sponsor segment over, but I still
have not received the
report from the Taipei Water Department.
I'm not really sure what to do now. I think
I have to actually stop recording
right now, then I'll get
back to you when I have a
reply from the report, and
see if we can actually drink
the water that I just drank
in the beginning of this video.
And now, a few days later, we are once again back
here at Taipei Water Department, since
we now finally got our water
results back. Let's go back home
to the studio and check it out.
Okay, so now we're back from Taipei Water
Department, and in my hand
I have, at least I hope
I have, my water report
which will tell me
that the tap water here in the apartment
is safe to drink.
Let's see. Notification of
water quality test results.
The water sample
scent were tested for turbidity,
no idea what that is, residual
chlorine, pH, and total
dissolved solids. And the results
were found to compliance to Taiwan's
drinking water quality standards.
The key to safe drinking water quality
lies in regular cleaning and maintenance of water equipment
such as water basins and rooftop water towers.
We recommend to clean and maintain water basins
and water towers at least once a year.
Well, we all know I'm not going to be the one cleaning
our rooftop water tower, but I
do hope that my landlord has
everything under control. Should you have any questions,
please contact us through our service hotline
and you'll have the number down there.
Whew, okay.
It looks like our drinking tap
water is up to Taiwan's
drinking water quality standards.
Yeah, they actually
said before that the report that you will
get is basically like yes or no.
Can you drink it or can you not?
If it's considered that you can
drink it, then this free test does
not include any more information
such as, for example,
whatever turbidity
means. No idea.
But yeah, so it turns out
that my whole life here
in Taiwan has been a lie because apparently
at least in this apartment
I have been able to actually
drink the tap water this whole time.
But then again, I barely drink
normal water anymore since I do try
to have a sparkling water
diet thanks to Celinda.
And once again, they do recommend that we
do have this filter tap system, which
we already have in the apartment.
So if I'm going to be completely honest,
I will continue using that
filter tap water into my
sparkling water machine and
continue my sparkling water diet.
But hopefully this helps
some of you Taiwanese people, but
also foreigners coming here.
One thing to actually know, if you can drink
the tap water here, at least in
Taipei or not. And I'm sure
that every other county, every other city
will have your own water departments
where you can just contact.
And they were super friendly.
They told me that they were a little surprised
I think seeing a foreigner walking
in there. So I don't think this is a service
that a lot of foreigners in Taiwan knows about.
And they said that most of the time,
if there has been a big accident or something
in the neighborhood or in a specific
building, then there would be a lot
of people coming at the same time.
So they have based on these situations.
And I'm pretty sure
that was the first time they saw
a foreigner walking in
just randomly asking.
Because the first question they said was like
What kind of water is this?
I'm like, YouTube video?
But yeah, they were super cool about it.
And it's free.
It's been a few days since I drank that
first glass of tap water.
Yeah.
All good. Cannot complain at all.
And hopefully you also
do not complain about this video. And in fact
if you do like this video, please do
click that like button to show your support.
Please also help me share this video with someone
who maybe want a little bit more information
regarding the tap water quality
at least here in Taipei or where you can
find out more information if you want to test
your own tap water here in Taiwan.
Thank you all so much for watching.
My name is Lukas. Starts with L
as in like. Ends with S as in
subscribe. Please do both.
And see you all in the next one.